Karan Balaji

karanarjunb@gmail.com · 437-331-6023 · Toronto · <u>Linkedin.com/in/karanbalaji</u> · <u>https://karanbalaji.com/</u>

Summary

- 2x AWS Cloud certified enthusiastic individual with 2 years in UX Design.
- Ux Design portfolio: https://karanbalaji.com/socialed/

Personal Projects

Karanbalaji.com - React.js, Gatsby.js, AWS S3, AWS CloudFront, Route 53.

https://blog.karanbalaji.com/ - Gatsby.js, AWS S3, Route 53, AWS ACM.

Operationunplugged - React.js, Chart.js (Visualization), CSS 3, GIT.

Columbia Zoo Problem -HTML5, CSS3 Bootstrap 3

College students - React.js, Css3, Material UI

Cultural Experience - React.js, Css3, Material UI

Work Experience

Product Designer (Ux)

June 2021 - November 2021

Bonnethood.com - Montreal, Canada

- Worked in agile methodology using Jira and designed re-usable components based on React Material UIs using Figma.
- Adding Hotjar tracking code and researching about user behavior.
- Created design theme based on Material Design on Figma.
- Designed the mobile UI based on material design standards and creating the landing page.
- Contributing in styled components (JSX) (Landing Page) and committing it on GitHub

Exploratory tester

Aug 2020 - Jan 2021 (6 months)

HomeStars - Toronto, Canada

- Reporting User Centric bugs on JIRA with creation of tickets and assigning to respective developers.
- Implemented hotjar analytics code on various pages to capture recordings.
- Responsible for testing code and checking if it is reflecting on sqlpro database.

Product Designer (Ux)

Aug 2019 - July 2020 (1.5 years)

ExamPro.co - Toronto, Canada

- Designed re-usable components on React Material UIs using Adobe XD.
- Designed landing pages with HTML5, CSS3 and Javascript.
- Added tracking code using Google Tag Manager and Google Analytics for landing pages.

- Improved the user experience by capturing over 100 UX issues with digital ethnography on the HotJar Analytical tool that which were documented on GitHub.
- Designed the marketing site intern page and reported over 10 UX issues on GitHub
- Organized using GitHub **project management** tool to create UX, Marketing and product tickets to assign issues for developers and designers, stakeholders (Founders).
- Identified product problems through research and made **personas** through interviews, surveys and ethnography to create a **personalized user experience**
- Created re-usable **design systems** on Adobe XD that improved prototyping speed between the designers and developers.

Education

SEPTEMBER 2018 - AUGUST 2019

INTERACTIVE MEDIA MANAGEMENT, CENTENNIAL COLLEGE - TORONTO, CANADA

JANUARY 2018 - SEPTEMBER 2018

MARKETING MANAGEMENT, CENTENNIAL COLLEGE - TORONTO, CANADA

JUNE 2014 - JULY 2017

BACHELORS OF COMMERCE, LOYOLA COLLEGE - CHENNAI, INDIA

Certifications

AWS Certified Solution Architect - Associate	2020
AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner	2019
Microsoft Enterprise Security Fundamentals	2019
Advanced Google Analytics Certification	2019
Google AdWords Fundamentals & Mobile	2019
Data Science: R Basics Harvard Certification	2019
Python for research Harvard Certification	2019
MIT Entrepreneurship Certification	2019

Volunteer

Toronto Solution Architect user group (Meetup.com)

Event Organizer

- Documented and conducted all tech talks on various social media.
- Delivered a tech talk on 4 ways of architecting A/B Testing on the AWS Cloud.

LinkedIn (Blogs hits)

• Empathy Design: https://www.linkedin.com/posts/karanbalaji_cx-google-ux-activity-6635915618728062976-mGZZ